<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nomad on Zein Hajj-Ali</title>
    <link>https://zeinhajjali.com/tags/nomad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nomad on Zein Hajj-Ali</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 13:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zeinhajjali.com/tags/nomad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NNSI: Northern Nomad Systems Integration Final Report</title>
      <link>https://zeinhajjali.com/projects/nnsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zeinhajjali.com/projects/nnsi/</guid>
      <description>The Northern Nomad Systems Integration (NNSI) project has ended, and the final report has been submitted to the supervising professor and second reader. The project did not warrant a Github page. Instead, I have made the final report available for reading here, or for download here.
Any questions about the project can be directed to me at zeinhajjali@outlook.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NNSI #2: Final Update &amp; Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://zeinhajjali.com/projects/nnsi2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 21:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zeinhajjali.com/projects/nnsi2/</guid>
      <description>The Northern Nomad Systems Integration project has ended, and the final report is close to finished. The team ran into a lot of setbacks, but that is to be expected from a real world project. Our main issue was that we were not given any documentation or compiled information about all the systems that are installed in the house. We decided to make our final report as comprehensive as possible and available to any future teams that will work on the Nomad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NNSI #1: Northern Nomad Systems Integration Project</title>
      <link>https://zeinhajjali.com/projects/nnsi1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zeinhajjali.com/projects/nnsi1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Starting September of 2018, I joined a project as my capstone engineering project at Carleton University. The project was led by Professor Donald Bailey and included 5 other team members as well as myself. The Northern Nomad Tiny House&amp;rsquo;s goals included independence from the internet, net-zero emissions, and net-zero water usage. The project was to integrate and develop the system used in the Northern Nomad Tiny House that was built on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>